<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>lewistehminerz's blog</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on lewistehminerz's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2021 Lewis Crichton</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 13:54:33 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Barriers to Communication</title><link>/posts/barriers-to-communication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 13:54:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/barriers-to-communication/</guid><description>This post is related to a college assignment about writing a blog post regarding barriers to effective communication.
When engaging in conversation with a person or audience, there are many barriers to communication that you have to keep in mind to preserve effective communication.
Language Barrier Not being able to speak the language that your audience uses means that they will not understand what you say.
Interpreters can help get over this issue but learning the language itself will help engage your audience more as they won’t have to keep swapping between speakers.</description><content>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;em>This post is related to a college assignment about writing a blog post regarding barriers to effective communication.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When engaging in conversation with a person or audience, there are many barriers to communication that you have to keep in mind to
preserve effective communication.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="language-barrier">Language Barrier&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Not being able to speak the language that your audience uses means that they will not understand what you say.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Interpreters can help get over this issue but learning the language itself will help engage your audience more as they won’t have
to keep swapping between speakers.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="auditory">Auditory&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>People will not be able to hear you if they are deaf. A sign language interpreter will help them understand your communication,
however, just like before, it&amp;rsquo;s preferable to learn sign language yourself and interpret live so that your audience doesn&amp;rsquo;t need
to swap between speakers.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="incoherence">Incoherence&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Mumbling, stuttering, and slurring your speech can make it completely incoherent and your audience will not be able to understand
you. Make sure to rehearse your speech and stay confident, and make sure to be clear so your audience can hear you. An alternative
is to have a teleprompter or a similar method of reading your script so that you can avoid misspeaking.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="disengagement">Disengagement&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>If your audience is not engaged with the communication, they will not absorb information or bother listening. Make your speech
interesting by adding things the audience can relate to whilst keeping it appropriate.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="distractions">Distractions&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>If you are attempting to establish communication in a distracting environment, your audience may be more interested in other
things if you don’t make your communication engaging. Reduce distractions as much as possible such as moving to a more closed
space.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="multimedia">Multimedia&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>If your communication doesn’t have multimedia (images, videos, audio) your audience may become disengaged with it. Adding
images and videos can emphasise parts of your communication and re-engage your audience. If you&amp;rsquo;re doing a PowerPoint, using
animations can also re-engage audience members.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="body-language">Body Language&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>If your audience sees your body language as negative, they will become disengaged and become negative themselves. Keep your body
language positive and engaging. Audiences tend to reflect your body language, so by using positive body language they will become
positive.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="informal-language">Informal Language&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Usage of words such as slang words can result in your communication being unintelligible for certain people who do not know what
the slang means. Keep your vocabulary simple and avoid terms that your audience may not understand. This makes it so everyone is
on the same page, and not just people from a certain community.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="unorganisaed">Unorganisaed&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>If you are stumbling through your communication because you never organised it or planned, your audience will not take you
seriously and will disengage. Plan and rehearse your communication to make sure you stay on track and don&amp;rsquo;t disengage the
audience. As before, you can use a teleprompter or some other method of reading a script to act as a point of reference.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="unpresentable">Unpresentable&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Without a proper presentation set up, your audience will not understand your communication well and may even completely
misunderstand what you say. Make sure your communication is presentable, either by practicing it to make sure it makes
sense, or with someone else and ask for feedback. Asking someone else for feedback also has the advantage of knowing how your
ideas came across to an audience.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Bunger</title><link>/posts/bunger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 16:07:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/bunger/</guid><description>Bunger is a simple bot. You say bunger (or any variation of it like Bunger!, bUnGeR, whatever) and you get this cute fella:
I got this idea from the owner of a Roblox game called ZO (very fun game by the way, you should give it a shot!). I was bored, and I built it. Seems like the game&amp;rsquo;s community took a liking to it as well, since they very much enjoy Bunger.</description><content>&lt;p>Bunger is a simple bot. You say &lt;code>bunger&lt;/code> (or any variation of it like &lt;code>Bunger!&lt;/code>, &lt;code>bUnGeR&lt;/code>, whatever) and you get this cute fella:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://lewistehminerz.dev/assets/img/bunger.gif" alt="bunger">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I got this idea from the owner of a Roblox game called &lt;a href="https://www.roblox.com/games/6678877691/ZO-WIP">ZO&lt;/a> (very fun game by the
way, you should give it a shot!). I was bored, and I built it. Seems like the game&amp;rsquo;s community took a liking to it as well, since
they &lt;em>very&lt;/em> much enjoy Bunger.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://discord.com/api/oauth2/authorize?client_id=856180135824719883&amp;amp;permissions=16384&amp;amp;scope=bot">Invite it?&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Hello, world!</title><link>/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 21:57:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>Our first lines of code that we ever write, Hello World has been our most common goto for writing. It&amp;rsquo;s also an expression used to announce your presence to the outside world that you exist. Here&amp;rsquo;s me doing just that.
Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m LewisTehMinerz. I&amp;rsquo;m a developer. You will find me here and on Discord, which is my primary social media application that I use. Most services I use I register under the same username so it&amp;rsquo;s always relatively easy to find me somewhere.</description><content>&lt;p>Our first lines of code that we ever write, Hello World has been our most common goto for writing. It&amp;rsquo;s also an expression used
to announce your presence to the outside world that you exist. Here&amp;rsquo;s me doing just that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;code>LewisTehMinerz&lt;/code>. I&amp;rsquo;m a developer. You will find me here and on Discord, which is my primary social media application
that I use. Most services I use I register under the same username so it&amp;rsquo;s always relatively easy to find me somewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyways, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what I&amp;rsquo;m going to be writing about yet. Probably just random things that I decide to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can &lt;a href="/about">read more about me&lt;/a> if you wish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll see you around.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description> Hi, it's me! Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Lewis, or more commonly known online as LewisTehMinerz. You&amp;rsquo;ve probably found me from my website or GitHub.
I develop (obviously) with many tools and languages and I am constantly experimenting with more. I haven&amp;rsquo;t written a killer project yet, but maybe one day I will.
Socials Twitter GitHub Discord: LewisTehMinerz#1337 And more! I use LewisTehMinerz as a common pseudonym.</description><content>
&lt;figure class="center" >
&lt;img src="https://lewistehminerz.dev/assets/img/oc.webp" style="max-width: 250px" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >Hi, it's me!&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Lewis, or more commonly known online as LewisTehMinerz. You&amp;rsquo;ve probably found me from my
website or &lt;a href="https://github.com/LewisTehMinerz">GitHub&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I develop (obviously) with many tools and languages and I am constantly experimenting with more. I
haven&amp;rsquo;t written a killer project yet, but maybe one day I will.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="socials">Socials&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LewisTehMinerz">Twitter&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/LewisTehMinerz">GitHub&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Discord: &lt;code>LewisTehMinerz#1337&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>And more! I use &lt;code>LewisTehMinerz&lt;/code> as a common pseudonym.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item></channel></rss>