<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>college on lewistehminerz's blog</title><link>/tags/college/</link><description>Recent content in college on lewistehminerz's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2021 Lewis Crichton</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 13:54:33 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/college/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Barriers to Communication</title><link>/posts/barriers-to-communication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 13:54:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/barriers-to-communication/</guid><description>This post is related to a college assignment about writing a blog post regarding barriers to effective communication.
When engaging in conversation with a person or audience, there are many barriers to communication that you have to keep in mind to preserve effective communication.
Language Barrier Not being able to speak the language that your audience uses means that they will not understand what you say.
Interpreters can help get over this issue but learning the language itself will help engage your audience more as they won’t have to keep swapping between speakers.</description><content>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;em>This post is related to a college assignment about writing a blog post regarding barriers to effective communication.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When engaging in conversation with a person or audience, there are many barriers to communication that you have to keep in mind to
preserve effective communication.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="language-barrier">Language Barrier&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Not being able to speak the language that your audience uses means that they will not understand what you say.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Interpreters can help get over this issue but learning the language itself will help engage your audience more as they won’t have
to keep swapping between speakers.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="auditory">Auditory&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>People will not be able to hear you if they are deaf. A sign language interpreter will help them understand your communication.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="incoherence">Incoherence&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Mumbling, stuttering, and slurring your speech can make it completely incoherent and your audience will not be able to understand
you. Make sure to rehearse your speech and stay confident, and make sure to be clear so your audience can hear you.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="disengagement">Disengagement&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>If your audience is not engaged with the communication, they will not absorb information or bother listening. Make your speech
interesting by adding things the audience can relate to.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="distractions">Distractions&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>If you are attempting to establish communication in a distracting environment, your audience may be more interested in other
things if you don’t make your communication engaging. Reduce distractions as much as possible such as moving to a more closed
space.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="multimedia">Multimedia&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>If your communication doesn’t have multimedia (images, videos, audio) your audience may become disengaged with it. Adding
images can emphasise parts of your communication and re-engage your audience.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="body-language">Body Language&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>If your audience sees your body language as negative, they will become disengaged. Keep your body language positive and
engaging.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="informal-language">Informal Language&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Usage of words such as slang words can result in your communication being unintelligible for certain people who do not know what
the slang means. Keep your vocabulary simple and avoid terms that your audience may not understand.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="unorganisaed">Unorganisaed&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>If you are stumbling through your communication because you never organised it or planned, your audience will not take you
seriously and will disengage. Plan and rehearse your communication to make sure you stay on track and don&amp;rsquo;t disengage the
audience.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="unpresentable">Unpresentable&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Without a proper presentation set up, your audience will not understand your communication well and may even completely
misunderstand what you say. Make sure your communication is presentable, either by practicing it to make sure it makes
sense, or with someone else and ask for feedback.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>