<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>zo on lewisakura's blog</title><link>/tags/zo/</link><description>Recent content in zo on lewisakura's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 Lewis Crichton</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 17:23:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/zo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Alpha1 v. b1nkster/ZOぞ</title><link>/posts/alpha1-v-b1nkster/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 17:23:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alpha1-v-b1nkster/</guid><description>I recently saw the case of Alpha1 and b1nkster/Ryan so I&amp;rsquo;m coming to give my two cents on it as part of ZOぞ&amp;rsquo;s management team.
This writeup exists purely because Alpha1 made a video on it. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have cared otherwise.
Alpha1 purposely told half-truths about the situation. A lot of what he claimed happened was true, but he left out important details to make the story go in his favour for him and his fanbase.</description><content>&lt;p>I recently saw the case of Alpha1 and b1nkster/Ryan so I&amp;rsquo;m coming to give my two cents on it as part of ZOぞ&amp;rsquo;s management team.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This writeup exists purely because Alpha1 made a video on it. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have cared otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alpha1 purposely told half-truths about the situation. A lot of what he claimed happened was true, but he left out important
details to make the story go in his favour for him and his fanbase. I assume the majority of this is under the guise of &amp;ldquo;family
friendly&amp;quot;ness but if you&amp;rsquo;re going to post things like this towards a staff team on your publicly linked Twitter and in the ITTO
Discord, you threw family friendly out of the window quite a bit ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All of the attached images from the ITTO Discord are publicly searchable and provable. They won&amp;rsquo;t be removed. I&amp;rsquo;ve also added my own
comments onto them. Let&amp;rsquo;s look through the events of this.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="the-buildup">The Buildup&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Alpha1 had an extremely loud audio and he initially got serverbanned for it by Ryan. This is considered fair by our standards; the
serverban means the reason is clearly seen and it stops Alpha1 from disturbing the users in the server again. From here, all he
had to do was join a different server, change his killsound, and all would be dandy. But no, this gets turned into a bigger deal
than it has to be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From here, Alpha1 proceeded to join the ITTO Discord server. Nothing wrong with this, maybe he wants to dispute his ban reasoning. I
suppose the best way to say what he did is that he wanted to dispute it, just not properly.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="itto">ITTO&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s begin with his introductory message (in #stage-chat for some reason).&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/LTifntH.png" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >Not unusual for someone who just got banned.&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>A community member asked what happened.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/ek6pjJD.png" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >Okay. We have a moderator and a reason why he got serverbanned.&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>At this point, another community member (I assume the reporter?) joins in (in #community).&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/eAYF0Ml.png" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >Alpha1's response is pretty hostile, and his refusal to change it because 'idgaf' is already a sign that he wasn't willing to cooperate with the staff team even if he was kindly asked. Maybe I'm wrong, though. Maybe if Ryan asked him then he might've done it, but the odds are that as soon as Ryan leaves he just changes it back, then a mod comes and punishes him for it, and then we end up here again. Who knows?&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Some irrelevant things were said like &amp;ldquo;cry more about it&amp;rdquo; and telling the reporter(?) to &amp;ldquo;shut the fuck up&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alpha1 then proceeds to tag the mod in question, calling his reason a &amp;ldquo;pathetic ass&amp;rdquo; reason.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/PbWKp1J.png" />
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Once Ryan gives his response, Alpha1 is quick to defend his audio choice.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/dogieRx.png" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >Audio used for 4 months? Must be allowed under the new policies!&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>After this, there are no more public messages from Alpha1. So, lets hop into some private DMs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="the-direct-messages">The Direct Messages&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The images in this section are small, apologies.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This part involves Alpha1 and Ryan&amp;rsquo;s DMs. You can look at
&lt;a href="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/860326435504128000/934860626419941447/unknown.png">the original screenshot&lt;/a> if you so wish,
but I hope I&amp;rsquo;ve made it a bit more readable here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alpha1 proceeded to DM Ryan. Let&amp;rsquo;s see his very polite introduction.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/L3Olnhx.png" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >Nice.&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Ryan responds, like he would usually do to any community member.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/43jhY9Z.png" />
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Alpha1 gives his justification for his lovely introduction, as well as his eventual harassment of Ryan.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/qogrWlS.png" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >Your YouTuber fame means nothing here. Everyone is treated equally.&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Ryan brushes it off. It&amp;rsquo;s not the first time people have done this sort of thing, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/MR82IYt.png" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >kk&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Alpha1 fires back with some insults that are bound to hurt!&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/DLzuGKl.png" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >Alpha1 uses INSULT! ...But it failed.&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>So&amp;hellip; Alpha1 comes back with an interesting proposal.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/74lvUHr.png" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >Bribery is a permanently bannable offence to begin with, so I hope you were joking. Also, everyone has to follow the same new rules. You don't get an exemption because you're 'grandfathered'. You don't have a 'right'. Rule changes aren't retroactive in ZOぞ, but if you continue to do something that is against the new ruleset, we have the right to punish you. You don't escape rules by trying to claim it was okay in the past, otherwise we'd have so many more rulebreakers.&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Ryan, being the good staff member he is, rejects it.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/9nm3Kqv.png" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >Good job!&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Now, Ryan asked a question. What&amp;rsquo;s Alpha&amp;rsquo;s response?&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/2Fahxvw.png" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >Yeah, okay. Ryan serverbanned you. That's not harassment. You joined ITTO and started harassing him because you got punished for breaking the rules. It doesn't work like that. Even if he did actually harass you, harassing him for harassing you is childish. We have a staff reports system for a reason.&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Ryan tells him what he had to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/tqY5N87.png" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >This is it, Alpha. This was all we asked.&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>To which Alpha straight up refuses.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/Daqv051.png" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >You were given your way out of this, and you refused to take it. Oh dear.&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Again, Alpha attempts to defend his audio choice.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/4ENQ8m5.png" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >Ryan isn't being biased against you, like you're implying here. You aren't being singled out from other people. We treat everyone equally. You got reported multiple times, Ryan came and did his job. Just because 1 person called you out in #community over it doesn't mean that there weren't multiple reports.&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Alpha demands proof, probably because he thinks his YouTuber status means something here.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/yp0TEwL.png" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >Our moderators do not need to disclose evidence if there is no valid reason to. This is not a valid reason.&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>And at this point, nothing else meaningful was going to happen. Alpha tried to get in some low blows and they got rejected.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/CevycaA.png" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >*yawn* Oh god, we're still going on? No? Finally.&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Ryan then proceeded to ban Alpha1 permanently from ZOぞ.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="the-aftermath">The Aftermath&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>After all of this went down, Alpha1 came to Twitter.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/1aqmgse.png" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >Oh for god sake I thought this was over.&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>The replies to this tweet are something else that I won&amp;rsquo;t cover, so you can &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/okalpha1/status/1475505228065624070">read it yourself&lt;/a>
if you so desire. I&amp;rsquo;ll follow the main thread.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zeek responded to this with a pretty simple message.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/Blydvw6.png" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >It's true!&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Alpha&amp;rsquo;s main response is the same argument he tried to use before. He had the audio before the rule change, so he should be allowed
to keep it!&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/fF0NJ0w.png" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >You already got rejected for using this, what makes you think it'll work here?&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>And Zeek hit back.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/iQbuOw8.png" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >I told you being a YouTuber is meaningless.&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Alpha proceeded to try and justify his actions.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/qXixsfH.png" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >Justifying harassment... yikes.&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>To which he got left on read. Ouch.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="my-thoughts">My Thoughts&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Alpha1 acted severely childish during this entire case. He couldn&amp;rsquo;t handle the truth that what he was doing wasn&amp;rsquo;t okay in the new
rules, and decided to try and resist to.. what, start a revolution or something? All he had to do was follow the moderator&amp;rsquo;s request,
but he tried to villainize us and make ITTO look like the bad guys. In his video, he leaves out several important aspects of the
case to try and make himself look good and to rally his fanbase behind the cause. Him proceeding to try and convince Zeek on Twitter
to get unbanned just because he&amp;rsquo;s a YouTuber is silly as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Regardless of your status, you are treated equal in this community. YouTuber or not, we aren&amp;rsquo;t afraid to issue the same punishments
to you as to everyone else. You can try and cancel us or whatever, but we will very much hit back if we have to. Alpha made a big
deal out of this, and I&amp;rsquo;m sitting here bored making this writeup just because I find the entire situation comical.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From a management member&amp;rsquo;s perspective, Ryan tried to deal with this situation as calmly as possible but Alpha was not willing to
cooperate. As such, his ban is justified. Alpha is no longer welcome in ITTO or ZOぞ, and neither are the people who try and defend
him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ITTO court is adjourned.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>